<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="page.xsl"?>
<root>
  <title>About iOS Coders</title>
  <subject name="Who We Are" collapsed="false">
    <node name="">
      <content>
        <p>The iOS Coders are a group of enthusiasts that meet regularly to
          discuss all aspects of writing iOS apps. Our primary purpose is to
          develop relationships with other iOS coders in the North Suburbs of
          Chicago.</p>
        <p>We have members at all levels of experience who are interested in
          helping each other get started or improve their skills. We also
          discuss marketing and ways to pass App Store reviews.</p>
        <p>Our meetings are casual and we spend a lot of time getting to know
          new members. All of our members write iOS apps for the fun of it.
          Some of us are professional programmers. Others are self-taught
          hobbists. Most commonly, members have experience with other
          programming languages and wish to start writing iOS apps.</p>
      </content>
    </node>
  </subject>
  <subject name="What We Do" collapsed="false">
    <node name="">
      <content>
        <p>Someone usually prepares a tutorial or demonstration, which lasts
          typically lasts about a half hour. Most of the members bring
          questions or problems they need help with. We usally spend a lot of
          time talking about how to help each other with these things.</p>
        <p>
          Material discussed is stored on the
          <site/>
          site, but will be moved to a
          server or a Dropbox.
        </p>
      </content>
    </node>
  </subject>
  <subject name="Projects" collapsed="false">
    <node name="">
      <content>
        <p>This app is available for anyone in the group to work on. We try to
          use much of the iOS framework as possible to make it the most
          comprehensive learning tool possible.</p>
      </content>
    </node>
  </subject>
  <subject name="Meetings" collapsed="false">
    <node name="">
      <content>
        We currently meeting the last Tuesday of every month at Starbucks in
        Libertyville. Usually about 4-6 people attend. We have space for up to
        8 attendees. Details are on the
        <site/>
        site.
      </content>
    </node>
  </subject>
  <subject name="Resources" collapsed="false">
    <node name="">
      <content>
       Resources are currently on the
        <site/>
        site.
      </content>
    </node>
  </subject>
  <subject name="Embedded Apps" collapsed="false">
    <node name="">
      <content>This app has a space for &quot;applets&quot;, basically an icon that will run an app inside itself.
        It&apos;s a good place for you to showcase your work or help others with theirs.
        Of course, you are free to put your standalone app on the App Store as well.</content>
    </node>
  </subject>
</root>
